urduword.com 2002-06-01

# UrduWord.com - About - Privacy Statement

| 

Please visit our sponsors. Advertisements open in new window  

This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for _UrduWord.com_ website.

| **Information Collection and Use**  
---  
| _UrduWord.com_ collects information from users at several different points on our website, whose details and usage information is elucidated in this privacy statement. We respect our users' privacy and will not use the information in ways other than specified here, unless we are required to do so by law or we believe that it is in the best of interests for us to (1) protect and defend our, and our general users', rights (2) prevent the misuse or unauthorized use of UrduWord.com.  
  **Contact Forms (General, Urgent, Feedback, Requests, Error Reports)**  
---  
| In order to contact us, users are asked to specify some information about themselves. Here, the required information includes **_name_** and **_e-mail address_**. The optional information includes **_designation/company_** and **_website_**. The feedback form also asks the user the **_source_** from where he/she found out about _UrduWord.com_. All this information is only used to better understand our users' queries and is **not stored, sold, rented, or shared** with a third-party. The optional e-mail address for Requests is only stored to _automatically inform_ the user when the request is fulfilled and is not shared with third-party. The _aggregate_ of sources specified by our users is used to obtain a general idea of which form of publicity best works for _UrduWord.com_ and is not used for personal identification purposes.  
  **Cookies**  
---  
| A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s hard drive containing information about the user. **We do not use any cookies on our website.**

Some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies. This information is only used to link our website to our advertisers and is not used for personal identification purposes.  
  
  **Log Files**  
---  
| We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. **IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.**

Likewise, we gather and analyze information such as words looked-up, web-browser used, time of access, and pages-accessed for _aggregate_ use. **Logged information is not linked to personally identifiable information.**  
  
  **Sharing**  
---  
| We only share **aggregated** information such as visits-per-day with our advertisers. **This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.**  
  **Web Links**  
---  
| This website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we _UrduWord.com_ are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. **This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this website.**  
  **Tell Your Friends About UrduWord.com**  
---  
| If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friends' name and email address. _UrduWord.com_ will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. _UrduWord.com_ uses this information for the **sole purpose of sending this one-time email**.  
  **Daily UrduWord - E-Mail Subscription**  
---  
| The _Daily UrduWord - E-mail Subscription_ only asks the user's e-mail address. This e-mail address is **used to send automated e-mails** and is **not sold, rented, or shared** with a third-party. _UrduWord.com_ may e-mail subscribers to inform them about changes to the system that may affect their subscription.
